ONUR KAPÇIK

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEAD | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER onurkapcik@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/onur-kapcik github.com/kapozade lzmir Turkey

Microservice Architecture, Backend Web Development, Object Oriented Design, Agile Methodologies, API Development, .NET Core, Unit Testing, TypeScript, JavaScript, Node.js, SQL, Python, Azure, AWS, Git I'm a software developer with more than 8 years of professional work experience with multinational teams.

I love coding, code reviewing, creating high quality of work and designing fault-tolerant systems, learning and working with agile teams. I have worked on both green-field and maintenance projects. I have a BS in Computer Engineering.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer, C Teleport

Aug 2023 - Ongoing, Remote

C Teleport is a travel agency to empower people through a flexible online travel management experience that is easy to use. My daily responsibilities are;

- Participating in daily standup meetings
- Enhance, maintain, and document our microservices according to functional and nonfunctional requirements
- Conducting code peer reviews with the team
- .NET Core, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Redis

Backend Team Lead, ÇiçekSepeti / Mizu

Jan 2022 - Apr 2023, Remote

CicekSepeti is the most visited floral and gifting website that serves in Turkey, Spain, Mexico and Colombia. As a backend team lead & senior software developer I'm responsible for implementing, reviewing microservices, and guiding team mates. My daily responsibilities are;

- Guiding team mates (includes tech and non-tech roles)
- Designing solutions on the microservices per user needs
- Creating and documenting our microservice inventory
- Reporting the optimisation of inner processes and errors to the software development managers
- .NET Core, TypeScript, NodeJS, Python, RabbitMQ, Redis, MySQL, MSSQL, AWS S3, AWS Lambda

Senior Software Developer, ÇiçekSepeti / Mizu

Dec 2020 - Apr 2023, Remote

- Participating in daily standup meetings
- Enhance and maintain our microservices according to functional and nonfunctional requirements
- Conducting code peer reviews with the team
- Documenting functional and technical requirements
- Conducting the analysis with business analyst to determine the user needs

Software Developer, Emakina

Nov 2016 - Oct 2020, Izmir, Turkey

Emakina is the user agency that serves all around the world. As a software developer I work with multinational agile and customer teams and use various CMS like Sitecore and Sitefinity. My daily responsibilities are;

- Participating in daily standup meetings, led by our Project Managers or Scrum Masters
- Enhance and maintain our clients CMS systems
- Conducting code peer reviews with my team and client team
- Pair programming with my team in necessary places
- Participating in feature demos, technical and functional analysis
- Documenting functional and technical requirements
- .NET MVC, Javascript, Sitecore, Sitefinity, Azure, MsSQL
- Worked with Sunweb, Kodak Alaris, Philip Morris International, Nationale Loterij.BE

Software Developer & Data Security Consultant, Komtaş

Jul 2015 - Oct 2016, Istanbul, Turkey

Komtaş empowers clients' digital transformation journey by driving data and analytics into the core of the client business. As a software developer and consultant I was working onsite in a client environment. My responsibilities are;

- Participating in meetings, led by clients' project owner or our customer team leads
- Implementing bash scripts & software plugins that work with Informatica services to bind customer environments to the Informatica platforms
- Participating in pre-sales technical activities for Vodafone and Garanti BBVA Bank
- Java, Informatica DDM, Informatica PowerCenter, Informatica DQ, Oracle, MSSQL, Teradata
- Worked with Turkcell, KuveyTurk Bank

EDUCATION

• Izmir Institute of Technology, Computer Engineering

Oct 2010 - June 2015, Izmir, Turkey